===============OP=================
===============ED=================
皇暦2017年
Imperial Calendar year 2017.
エリア11と名付けられた植民地　日本は
The colony of Japan,
now named Area 11,
宗主国　神聖ブリタニア帝国に対し　独立戦争を挑んだ
declared a war of independence against...
the suzerain state of
the Holy Britannian Empire.
ブラックリベリオンと名付けられたこの内乱は
歴史上日本二度目の敗北として幕を閉じる
This uprising,
dubbed the Black Rebellion,
ended with a second historic defeat for Japan.
それから1年後　死んだはずのテロリスト
ゼロを名乗る男がエリア11に現れた
One year has passed.
The terrorist known as Zero, presumed
dead, has again appeared in Area 11.
武装集団　黒の騎士団を率いるゼロ　その正体こそ
ブリタニア帝国の捨てられた皇子　ルルーシュ·ランペルージである
Zero, who leads the armed group
known as the Black Knights.
His true identity:
Lelouch Lamperouge, the abandoned
prince of the Britannian Empire.
朝も夜も恋い焦がれて
Asa mo yoru mo koikogarete
Morning and night, I long for you
星になるよ 君守る
hoshi ni naru yo kimi mamoru
I'll become a star and protect you
戦いは行方知らず
tatakai wa yukue shirazu
No matter where the battle may take me
ashita to kinou no kousaten de
At the intersection of tomorrow and yesterday
明日と昨日の交差点で
交わらない君と僕
majiwaranai kimi to boku
You and I can't be together
今行くよ 僕は流れ星
ima iku yo boku wa nagareboshi
I'm a shooting star, on my way right now
世界が朽ち果てても 変わることの無いものがある
sekai ga kuchihatetemo
Even if the world crumbles apart
kawaru koto no nai mono ga aru
There are things which will never change
涙を堪えてでも 守るべきものが僕らにはある
namida wo koraete demo
Even as we bear tears in our eyes
mamorubeki mono ga bokura ni wa aru
There are things we must protect
（nononono）
nanman'nen nan'okunen mae kara no
A message that's been in my body
遅れまいと メッセージが絶えない
（no）
message ga tainai de
For thousands and millions of years,
剥き出す 撃ち抜く
uzukidasu... mayoi wa nai
Springs out... I have no reservations
（迷いは無い）
narihibiku... kantan da
Roars out... It's easy
（簡単だ）
shagareta koe de... asu wo yobu
In a hoarse voice... Calling tomorrow
しゃがれた声で 傷だらけの手で 君守る
kizudarake no te de... kimi mamoru
With my wounded hands... I protect you
way got you could like
I continue to fight...
I continue to fight!
朝も夜も恋い焦がれて
asa mo yoru mo koikogarete
Morning and night, I long for you
星になるよ 君守る
hoshi ni naru yo kimi mamoru
I'll become a star and protect you
戦いは行方知らず
tatakai wa yukue shirazu
No matter where the battle may take me
明日と昨日の交差点で
ashita to kinou no kousaten de
At the intersection of tomorrow and yesterday
交わらない君と僕
majiwaranai kimi to boku
You and I can't be together
宿命を切り裂く流れ星
sadame wo kirisaku nagareboshi
I'm a shooting star, tearing fate apart
afureru kimi no namida boku ga ima ubaisaru
I'll take away your overflowing tears right now
溢れる君の涙 僕が今奪い去る
IMPRISONED IN CAMPUS
私はここに合衆国日本の建国を再び宣言する
I once again, here and now declare the
founding of the United States of Japan!
この瞬間より　この部屋が合衆国日本の最初の領土となる
From this moment, this room shall
be the first dominion of the U.S.J.!
人種も主義も宗教も問わない　国民たる資格はただ一つ
Race, ideology, and religion will not matter!
Being a citizen will have but one requirement!
正義を行うことだ
To do that which is just!
殺しに来ました　ゼロを
That's why I came. To kill Zero.
電話です　ただの
It's my phone. Nothing more.
ロロ　大丈夫か
Rolo! Are you okay?!
あっ　兄さん
Big brother?!
よかった　連絡が取れないから　心配したんだぞ
Thank goodness! I was worried
because I couldn't contact you.
無事なんだな　安全な所にいるのか
You aren't hurt, are you?
You're someplace safe, right?
どういうことなんだ　今演説しているゼロは別人
What's going on here?
Is the Zero making the speech
right now a different person?
兄さん　今　どこにいるの
Big brother, where are you right now?
何言ってるんだ　お前こそ　今…
What are you talking about, especially since you're...
ロロ　私だ
Rolo, it's me.
ヴィレッタ先生
Ms. Villetta?!
ルルーシュは学校に戻ってるぞ　これから補修だ
Lelouch came back to school.
He's taking his makeup classes.
お前も早く戻って来い
Get back here soon.
はい　分かりました
Right. Understood.
電話は終わりか　少年
Is your call finished, kid?
終わったみたいです　いろいろと
It looks like all my business here is finished.
黒の騎士団の残党とゼロを名乗る人物は
いまだ中華連邦総領事館の一部に立てこもっています
The remnants of the Black Knights
and the person claiming to be Zero...
are currently hiding in a section of
the Chinese Federation consulate.
しかし　ご安心ください
However, there is no need for concern.
負傷したカラレス総督に代わって
ギルフォード総督代行が率いる軍が完全に領事館を包囲しております
Acting Viceroy Guilford has taken command of the
army in place of the wounded Viceroy Calares...
and has the consulate completely surrounded.
これで　租界の安全は確保されたと言えるでしょう
We've been assured that the
settlement is in no danger.
すごい騒ぎね　ルルーシュ
You've really got the town jumping, Lelouch.
当然だろう　自分たちの領土の中に　突然国ができたんだ
Naturally.
A new nation has just been
created in their own territory.
しかもその国が宣戦布告してきたとあってはな
Not to mention it also just declared war on them.
なんだ
What?
いつの間に入れ替わってたの
When did you switch places with him?!
演説の前
Before the speech.
えっ　だって…
But!
声は録音　現れた時点ですでに別人
His voice was recorded. The moment "he"
appeared, it was already someone else.
マジックショーと同じだな
Just like in a magic show, right?
気に入らないわね　私たちにまで秘密にするなんて
We don't like things like that
being kept secret from us!
私たち？　私に　だろう
"We" don't like it? You mean
"I don't like it," don't you?
ルルーシュ　オーブン
Lelouch, oven!
はいはい
Sure thing.
塩
Salt.
フライパン
Frying pan.
卵
Egg.
ベシャメルソース
Bechemel sauce.
ジェラートは別皿
Put the gelato on another plate.
Oh, and add the rosemary to the sorbet.
ああ…ローズマリーを出してソルベに
それと　ザワークラウトはディルシードね
Then add the dill seed to the sauerkraut.
Schwarzwälder Kirschtorte needs...
シュヴァルツヴェルダーキルシュトルテは…
無理ですよ　そんなに
I can't handle all that myself!
どうして　オレだけ　こんなに
Why do you just ask me to do all this?!
しかたないでしょ　リヴァルは味音痴だし
I had no choice. Rivalz has no sense
of taste, and that leaves us with...
もう一人は…
細かいことは苦手でしたね　よく分かりました
With someone who's all thumbs.
I understand perfectly.
ん　素直でよろしい
Ooh, good. Nice and obedient.
にしても　この手のキャラは
生活力がないってのが　お約束なんだけどね
Characters like you are usually shown
not having any skills to make a living.
家計簿までつけてるからなぁ
But he even keeps a
household account book.
なぜ知っている
How did you know that?!
うわっ　ほんとだったの？
Oh, jeez, you really do?!
タオル　いる？
Want a towel?
自分でやります
I'll get it myself!
会長　聞いていいですか
Miss President, may I ask you something?
答えないかもしれないけど　いいよ
Sure, although I may not answer you.
今日はオレとロロの生還記念日パーティーですよね
Today we're having a party to celebrate
me and Rolo getting back alive, correct?
うん　テロ事件からよくぞ　生還した
Uh-huh! You both made it back from
that terrorist attack in one piece!
もう　シャーリーなんて　大変だったんだから
Poor Shirley was practically going out of her mind!
私…ルルが死んだら…
"Oh! If Lulu is dead, I'll!"
そういや　ロロは
Speaking of which, where is Rolo, anyway?
声は掛けたんだけど
ほら　兄と違ってナイーブで
I spoke with him, but... You know, he's a
lot more sensitive than his big brother.
そんなんだから　友達いないんじゃないの
That's part of why he doesn't
have any friends, isn't it?
おとなしいって言ってあげなよ
You should just say that he's quiet!
あの　付いてんだけど　いろいろと
Um, not that I mind you hanging on to me, but...
あっ　ごめんなさい
Oh. Sorry.
ほら　ベタベタになっちゃったじゃない
みんなナナリーのことを覚えていない
Nobody remembers anything about Nunnally.
いや　妹のナナリーが偽りの弟にすり替わっている
No, my little sister Nunnally has been
replaced by a phony little brother.
オレの記憶を変えただけではなく
生徒会のみんなまで　おもちゃに
I wasn't the only one whose memory was rewritten.
Everyone in the student council
has been toyed with as well!
なんてことを…
How dare they!
バベルタワーの事件以降もルルーシュ·ランペルージに特段の変化は見られません
Even after the Babel Tower incident, Lelouch
Lamperouge has shown no special changes.
校内には　180の隠しカメラ　偽装した監視者も47名
There are 180 hidden cameras on campus.
As well as 47 undercover observers.
監視者は48名
48 observers.
カルタゴ隊の全滅とルルーシュを結びつける情報は今のところ　存在しません
We've found no evidence linking Lelouch
with the destruction of Carthage unit.
監視は完ぺき　ギアスを使う透き間もない
The surveillance is perfect.
He has no chance to use his Geass.
ヤツがゼロなら学校に戻ってくるのも妙だし
If he is Zero, it would be odd
of him to return to this school.
結局C.C.は　どこにいるんですか
So, ultimately, where is C.C.?
ルルーシュと接触していないとしたら　総領事館にいる可能性は低い
If she isn't in contact with Lelouch, then...
The odds are low that she'd be in the consulate.
つまり　事件前と一緒　どこにいるか分からない
In other words,
we haven't made any progress.
We still don't know where she is?
我ら機密情報局はC.C.捕獲作戦を続行する
We in the Office of Secret Intelligence will
continue the operation to capture C.C.!
各員　これまでどおり餌の監視を続けよ
Everyone, continue to observe
the bait, as we were before.
イエス　マイ　ロード
Yes, My Lord!
敵の中枢は監視データの送信先
The enemy's center is where their
surveillance data is transmitted.
ここまでは　いい
I can just keep acting the way I have
been. The problem is Nunnally.
問題はナナリーだ
みんなからナナリーに関する記憶を奪ったのは
学校にナナリーが現れないと知っているから
The fact that all memory of Nunnally
has been removed from everyone...
tells me that Nunnally would
never show up at this school.
つまり　ブリタニア皇帝がナナリーを握っている可能性が高い
In short, the probability is high that the
Britannian emperor has Nunnally now.
相手は実の子供ですら道具として使う男だ
I'm dealing with a man who'd
use his own children as tools.
オレの記憶が…
If they learn I've regained my memories...
オレがゼロに戻ったと知られたら　ナナリーが危ない
That I've gone back to being
Zero, Nunnally will be in danger!
下手には動けない
I have to move very carefully.
あざむくんだ　オレを監視している連中を　それから…
I'll trick the people they have
spying on me. And then...
ルルーシュ
Lelouch?
明日の授業も　ちゃんと受けろよ
Make sure you come to class tomorrow.
分かってますよ　そんなに信用ないですか　オレって
I hear you.
Do you have so little faith in me?
ヴィレッタ·ヌウ　かつてオレがギアスをかけた女
Villetta Nu. A woman I once used my Geass on.
俺のギアスは1人に対し1回しか使えない
I can use my Geass on a person only once.
つまり　こいつには　もうギアスは通じない
Which means it won't work on her anymore.
ならば　存在しないはずの弟
まずはこいつから優しく攻略してあげようか
That leaves my little brother
who shouldn't even exist.
Why don't I begin by gently subduing him?
左翼　ドイツ州軍が攻勢に移りました
German state forces on the right
flank are taking the offensive!
オランダ工兵　地雷原　制圧
右翼も　イタリア州軍にしては　よく持ちこたえている
The Italian state forces are holding
out well on the right flank, too.
今夜のボルドーは勝利の美酒となりそうですね
The Bordeaux we drink tonight
will be a victorious fine vintage!
直上より　未確認　1
Unknown, approaching from above!
何っ
What?!
ランスロット
Lancelot!
ブリタニアの白き死神
The White Death of Britannia!
ラウンズが前線に！？
The Rounds have come to the front line?!
降伏してください　勝敗は決しました
Please surrender.
You have no chance of winning.
武器を捨てた者を　自分は撃ちません
I won't shoot anyone who lays down his weapon.
ふ　ふざけるな
Of all the impertinent!
討ち取れ　敵はたった一騎だぞ
Destroy him! It's just one knight!
残念です
So be it.
まだ続けるつもりですか
Want more?!
よろしいのですか　単独作戦行動など
Are you sure about this? Letting
him conduct a solo operation?
もともと枢木は　殿下の部下で
Kururugi was originally your
subordinate, Your Highness.
今はナイトオブセブン　皇帝陛下の直属だよ
He's now the Knight of Seven and
reports directly to His Majesty.
しかし…
But...
喜ぶべきことだろう　彼の栄進は
His promotion is something
to be happy about, isn't it?
世界はいまだ悲しみであふれている
The world as it is is overflowing with sadness.
彼には道しるべとしての自覚と責任感があるのだから
That's why he uses his self-consciousness
and sense of duty as guideposts.
ニーナがいない　アーサーはスザクが連れていったのか
Nina's gone, too. I wonder if
Suzaku took Arthur with him.
どうしたの　アルバムなんて
What's up? Why are you looking through the album?
それ　生徒会のマラソンダンスのファイルでしょ
That's the student council
marathon dance file, isn't it?
会長のイベント好きにも困ったもんだよ
The Prez runs us ragged with all
these events she likes to put on.
Oh, that's the Broken Heart Contest.
失恋コンテスト
泣けるよな
Sad, isn't it? How the Prez presented
Rivalz with the trophy after he won.
優勝したリヴァルにトロフィーを渡すのが　会長だなんて
よく　逃げられたね
Funny, how you managed to escape.
ニュースで言ってたでしょ　バベルタワーは軍が完全に包囲してたって
You heard the news, didn't you?
The military had Babel Tower
completely surrounded.
兄さんはどうやって包囲を破ったの
How'd you make it past them?
何言ってるんだよ　ロロ
What are you talking about, Rolo?
それを言うなら　どうやって　テロリストから逃げたかだろ
Don't you mean you want to know
how I got away from the terrorists?
非常通路があってさ　お前に連絡しようとしたんだけど
あの状態じゃ携帯はさ…
There was an emergency passageway.
I tried calling you, but my cell phone
wasn't working in that situation.
そう
I see...
そうだ　そのロケットは誕生日プレゼントにオレが渡したんだ
That's right... I gave him that locket for his birthday.
いや　違う
No, that's wrong.
あの日は　10月25日は　ナナリーの誕生日
That day... October 25th is Nunnally's birthday!
ロロ　そのロケット
Rolo, that locket...
よく考えたら　男にロケットってのもな…
When you think about it, a locket isn't something
you give to a guy. I'll get you something else...
もっと別の…
ダメだよ　これは　僕がもらったんだ
Don't take this! You gave it to me!
だから…僕のなんだ
That makes it mine, so!
ああ…分かったよ　ロロ
Uh... R- Right. Okay then, Rolo.
はい　ルルーシュの監視状況に変化はありません
Right, there's been no observed
change in Lelouch's behavior.
ギアスを使った形跡も皆無です
There are no indications that he's used his Geass.
ギアスの詳細は私には分からん　教団の…
I don't know the details of Geass.
It's a religious matter, so...
あ　お話中のようでしたら　あとで…
I can see you're talking. It can wait...
よせ　ロロ　同じミッションの仲間なんだから…
Rolo, no! He's on the same mission we are, so...
上の指示を…
...wait for orders from the higher-ups!
聞かれた可能性があります
There's a chance he heard us.
ギアスのことは　トウキョウセクションでも僕らだけの機密ですから
Knowledge of Geass is restricted
to only us two in the Tokyo section!
しかし　これで　何人の隊員を…
But, still... How many of our
agents have you killed so far?
最も確実で　迅速な方法でした　違いますか
It was the fastest and most certain method
to keeping the secret. Or am I wrong?
合衆国日本の成立からすでに3日がたつ
It's been three days since the United
States of Japan was established.
いつまでもブリタニアがにらみ合いを続けてくれるとは思えない
I doubt Britannia is just going
to keep glaring at us forever.
中華連邦本国でも総領事更迭の動きがある
There's even talk of recalling the consul general
back in the Chinese Federation homeland.
なのに　いまだルルーシュから　次の指示は来ていない
Even so, we haven't received
any instructions from Lelouch.
一体何を
What on earth is he doing?
あなたは　ゼロなんでしょ
You really are Zero, aren't you?
あ　そっか
Of course!
ブリタニアからの引き渡し交渉は遅滞させています
1週間程度は　もつかと
I'll drag out the extradition
negotiations with the Britannians.
I may be able to buy us up to a week.
ゼロに伝えておく　それより　中華連邦政府の…
I'll relay that to Zero. Now, as to the
Chinese Federation government's...
C.C.
C.C.! Why is that? Wouldn't it have made more
sense for you to have played the bunny girl?!
考えてみたら　あんたが
バニーやった方が　話し早かったんじゃないの
ゼロは　女
Zero is... a girl?!
そうだ
Yes.
違います
I'm not Zero!
バラすのが早すぎる　遊び心のない女だ
You let on too soon! You have
no sense of fun, do you?
ゼロで遊ばないで
Don't play around with Zero!
見えるぞ
We can see you.
はじめまして　紅月カレンさん
A pleasure to meet you, Miss Kallen Kouzuki.
紅蓮弐式のパイロットですよね
You're the pilot of the Guren Mk-II, aren't you?
えっ　どうして
How?
興味があるんです　あなたたちに
I have an interest in you people.
大変です　扇さんたちが…
Trouble! It's Ohgi and the others!
聞こえるか　ゼロよ
Can you hear me, Zero?
私は　コーネリア·リ·ブリタニア皇女が騎士
I am Lord Gilbert G.P. Guilford, knight of
her royal highness Cornelia li Britannia!
ギルバート·GP·ギルフォードである
明日15時より
国家反逆罪を犯した特一級犯罪者　256名の処刑を行う
Starting tomorrow at 15:00 hours,
all 256 of these special class A felons
guilty of rebellion against the homeland...
みんな…
Guys...
will be executed for their crimes!
ゼロよ　貴様が部下の命を惜しむなら
この私と　正々堂々と勝負をせよ
Zero! If you value
the lives of your people,
then you will face me
in a fair and honorable duel!
ギルフォード　やってくれる
Guilford... You've really gone and done it now.
あれ　ルル1人
Oh? Lulu, are you alone?
ああ　シャーリーこそ水泳部は
Yeah. Don't you have swim club, Shirley?
それがさぁ　私誕生日プレゼント買う係になっちゃって
Well, about that... I need to buy a birthday present.
誕生日？
Birthday?
顧問のヴィレッタ先生
For our advisor, Ms. Villetta.
私だけいつも怒られてるから　ちょうどいいって　みんなに
Everyone says I should get it since
I always make her mad at me.
でも苦手なんだよねぇ　プレゼントとか選ぶの
The thing is, I'm terrible at picking out presents.
やっぱり　お酒かな　好きみたいだし
I suppose I should buy her some
liquor. She seems to like it.
でも銘柄なんて…
But what brand should I get?
つきあおうか
Shall I come along?
えっ？
だから　プレゼント選ぶの
To help pick out the present.
えっ　い　いいの　ほんとに
Y-You would? Seriously?!
これから行くんだろ
You were about to go, right?
Y-Yeah! Yeah!
ネタの提供ありがとうございま～す
Thanks for the scoop, guys!
止まらなくなった　お前のギアスを防いでくれる
This is for protection from your Geass,
now that you can't turn it off.
光情報を遮断するだけでいいのなら
Since it only has to block optical information,
an ordinary color contact lens should be fine.
普通のカラーコンタクトでも
探りの会話は　よせ
Stop trying to probe me for information.
察しているとおり　それはスペシャルだ
As you guess, that lens is special.
しかし　お前のギアスが今よりも強くなったら
However, if your Geass grows
stronger than it is now, then...
それまでにはケリをつけるさ
Then we'll just have to finish
this game. Before that happens.
このゲームに
出かけるの
You're going out?
プレゼント選びの手伝い
I'm helping to pick out a present.
It's Ms. Villetta's birthday.
ヴィレッタ先生の誕生日なんだ
誕生日？
Birthday? I see.
そう　大事だよね　誕生日は
Birthdays are important, aren't they?
じゃあ　行ってくる
Well, I'd better get going.
いってらっしゃい
See you later.
ロロ
Rolo!
生徒会長
Miss President!
ロロ　あんたも来なさい
Rolo, you come, too! For communication!
コミュニケーションよ
Hm... I don't have any firsthand
knowledge about this.
オレも知識だけだから
しょうがないんじゃない
That can't be helped, can it? How about this stuff?
その辺は
貴腐ワインだと　甘口すぎるかな
（貴腐ワイン:甘口の白葡萄酒）
That's supposed to be a fine wine, but it
might be too sweet. How about a Sopron?
ショプロンあたりか
（ショプロン(sopron)はハンガリー北西端の町、
ワインの生産地として栄えている）
デート？
A date... Is this a date?
これって　デートかな？
デートかも
Maybe it is... Fine, I'll make it one, then!
よし　デートにするぞ
計算どおりだが
Just as I expected, although I didn't expect
them to bring Rolo, too. Typical Prez...
まさかロロまで連れてくるなんて
会長らしいな
男女交流生態学会のいい発表材料になりそうね
This'll make for a great presentation at the
Society for Research on Male-Female Dating.
R-Right...
だからって　兄貴の尾行に誘いますか
Even so, you sure you want
to follow your own brother?
ロロだって　興味あるでしょ
Rolo's interested too, isn't he?
ひょっとしたら　家族になるかも
She may end up joining the family, after all!
Yeah, that's right!
家族…
Family...
対象は　想定ルートＺを通過
Target is taking assumed route "Zebra."
よし　7班と交代
Right, switch off with group 7.
2班はC.C.の接触を警戒せよ
Group 2, be on guard for contact with C.C.
イエス　マイ　ロード
Yes, My Lord. Cleaning the perimeter.
周辺クリーニングに入ります
本当にゼロじゃないんだろうか
Is he really not Zero?
わざわざバベルタワーで罠を張った
They specifically set a trap at Babel Tower.
つまり　敵は　租界の総督府ではない
Which means my enemy isn't the
settlement's viceregal government.
さすがに　誰が監視者かは分からせないが
While I can't tell for
certain who's watching me,
システムそのものには透き間がある
the system itself that
they're using has flaws in it.
ゼロなら
If he is Zero, he wouldn't just ignore
the execution of his people tomorrow.
明日の部下の処刑を見過ごせないはず
やはり　記憶は戻っていないのか
Maybe he really hasn't gotten his memory back.
あの　ここは　どう書けば
Excuse me.
How do I fill out this bit here?
はい？
Pardon?
すみません　お願いしてもいいですか
I'm sorry, but could you do me a favor?
はい　なんでしょうか
Sure. What is it?
実はですね…
Well, it's like this...
お待たせ
Sorry for the wait.
何見てたんだ
What were you looking at?
えっ…あっ　あの…あれ
Oh! Um, uh... That!
ケ　ケーブルカーって　一度　乗ってみたいなぁ～って
l- I was just wishing I could
take a ride on a cable car once.
オレのせいだ
It's my fault.
オレのせいで　シャーリーは記憶を
My fault that Shirley's memories were wiped.
君がそばいれば
会長もリヴァルも記憶を勝手につくり替えられて
The Prez and Rivalz, too! Their memories
rewritten without their consent!
いつまでも　このままじゃいけない
You're My Destiny
I can't just let things go on like this.
すべてが終わったら　きっと君を…
ココロを開けて
When this is all over,
I swear I'll make it up to you.
打ち明けたいゆずれない想いを
どうしたの
What's the matter?
会長たちがつけてる
The Prez and the others are following us.
えっ　うそ
You're My Destiny
No way!
シャーリー
Shirley.
感じるキズナ
オレにいい考えがある
I've got a great idea.
二人の出会い運命なんだ
対象が　店舗に入ります
Target entering shop. Alpha-14, a small shop.
アルファ14　小さな店です
店内だと　察知される危険が
There's a risk of my cover being blown in there.
店舗前で待機
Cover the front. I'll send three
people to cover the rear.
裏側へ　3人回れ
しばらくここでオレが　中にいる振りをしてくれないか
Could you act like I'm in here for a while?
どういうこと
What's going on?
こっそり　店を出て会長たちを驚かしてくる
I'm going to sneak out of the store
and surprise the Prez and the others.
うん　分かった
Sure! Gotcha!
ふだん　オレが使わない店
This isn't a shop I normally use.
ここなら　監視カメラも　盗聴器もないはず
It shouldn't have any observation
cameras or listening devices.
シャーリーは他愛のないいたずらだと思っている
Shirley thinks this is just a harmless prank.
万が一失敗しても　彼女に迷惑は掛からない
Even on the off-chance that something goes wrong,
I won't cause any trouble for her.
ギアスの仕込みも済んだ
I've made my preparations using my Geass.
All that's left now is...
あとは…
はい　表参道モール警備室です
Hello, Omotesando Mall security.
えっ　黒の騎士団？
What? The Black Knights?!
以下の要求に従わない場合
If you do not meet the following demands,
そちらに仕掛けた爆弾を爆発させる
we will detonate a bomb we have planted there.
違う　ゼロのはずがない
No... He can't be Zero!
ハコダテ租界より　お越しのマクシミリアン様
Mr. Maximillian from the Hakodate settlement.
これって？
お電話が入っております
That's!
テロの警戒…
A terror warning!
きっと黒の騎士団よ
It must be the Black Knights!
ゼロが復活したし
Zero's returned!
声が大きい　お客様に気づかれる
Keep your voices down! The customers will hear!
だって…
But!
表参道モールに黒の騎士団より爆破予告です
There's been a bomb threat
made to Omotesando Mall!
配置は動かすな　C.C.の接触に備えろ
Hold your positions! Prepare for contact from C.C.!
条件はクリア
All conditions have been cleared.
All that's left is the ignition switch.
あとは　点火ボタンだけ
10　9　8　7　6
Ten...
Nine...
Eight...
Seven...
Six...
5　4　3　2　1
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
黒の騎士団
The Black Knights!
テロ？
Terrorists?!
ああ　なんだ　これは
What's going on?!
しまった
Oh, hell!
な　なんだ
What the hell?!
ロロ
Rolo!
離れないで
Don't run off!
ロロ？
Rolo?
いない？
Not here?!
対象を見失いました
We've lost the target!
スコーピオンからの報告はどうしますか
What about that
report from Scorpion?!
ロロは
Where's Rolo?!
治安維持のため　携帯に緊急ジャミングが
All cell phones are being
jammed to maintain public order!
中佐　スコーピオンからの報告は最優先では…
Lt. Colonel! Does the report
from Scorpion have top priority?
私が現場に向かう
I'm going there myself!
パニックというのは　こうやって　つくるんだよ
And that is how you cause a panic.
兄さんの位置は
What's my brother's location?!
誰も…いない？
Nobody's here?
C.C.を捜しに行ったんだよ
They've gone looking for C.C....
やっぱり　目覚めていたの
So, you have awakened, after all.
尾行者をオレの奴隷に　絶対支配下に置かせてもらった
I made the man following me my slave
and put him under my absolute control.
やはりお前たちはC.C.の捕獲が最優先らしい
As I thought, your top priority is the capture of C.C....
たとえ　間違った情報でも
No matter how wrong the information you get is.
この鳥かごみたいな学園は
今から　オレの自由の城になる
Starting now, this gilded cage of a school
will become my castle of freedom.
そして　お前はナナリーを捜すための駒になってもらう
And as for you...
I'll make you my pawn to find Nunnally.
何
What?!
ギアス？
Geass?!
時を止めた？
You stopped time?!
ルルーシュ　その悪魔の瞳と共に
Lelouch... Now you and your devilish eye...
死ね
will die.
大変です　ゼロ
Zero! Emergency!
中華連邦が突然…
The Chinese Federation just suddenly...
黒の騎士団は　ここで滅びよ
Here and now, the Black Knights will be destroyed!
胸の中 いつか拾った
Mune no naka itsuka hirotta
Someday let's try to pick up and rebuild
幸せの欠片 集めてみよう
Shiawase no kakera atsumete miyou
The fragments of happiness in our hearts
忘れかけていたメロディー
Wasurekaketeita melody
That nearly forgotten melody
色褪せず僕の真ん中に
Iroasezu boku no man'naka ni
Stay vivid, deep inside of me
ありがとう 心から 僕に今があるのはみんなのおかげさ
Arigatou kokoro kara
I thank you from the bottom of my heart
Boku ni ima ga aru no wa minna no okagesa
Everything I have now, I owe to everyone
ありがとう 心から 次は僕がみんなにハッピー贈るよ
Arigatou kokoro kara
I thank you from the bottom of my heart
Tsugi wa boku ga minna ni happy okuru yo
Next I'll send happiness to everyone
何もかも忘れないよ あの日の僕も僕だから
Nanimokamo wasurenai yo
I won't forget anything
Ano hi no boku mo boku dakara
Because I'm still the same as I was that day
「大好きだよ」って　いつも言ってあげなきゃ駄目だね
Daisuki da yo'tte itsumo
You need me to keep on saying
Itte agenakya dame da ne
How much I love you
涙がこぼれそうな長い夜は ふっと振り返って
Namida ga kobore sou na nagai yoru wa
On those long nights, your tears about to overflow
Futto furikaette
Just turn around
足跡を辿るんだ あの日を忘れないように
Ashiato wo tadorun'da
Follow those footprints
Ano hi wo wasurenai you ni
So that you'll never forget that day
黒の騎士団の中核が　処刑されようとしている
The members Guilford is about to
execute are the core of the Black Knights!
なんとしても　助け出さねばならないが
今は　ロロが問題だ
The people I need to carry out my plan!
いや　突破口はあるはず
記憶を書き換えられた　みんなのためにも
Somehow, I have to save them.
オレは…
But right now, my phony little
brother Rolo is the problem.
They've deployed a
Geass-user to watch me.
Their plan makes sense.
But that power of his...
No, there's a breach I can exploit.
For the sake of everyone whose
memories were rewritten, I have to!
COUNTERATTACK AT THE GALLOWS